# LEO RONDEAU

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

c: 701-871-1056 leorondeau2020@gmail.com <u>leorondeau.io</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/leo-rondeau</u> <u>github.com/leorondeau</u> Nashville TN

## **ABOUT**

Before I entered into software development I worked as a songwriter and singer, touring the US and internationally. After the world came to a stop in 2020 I started coding and enjoyed it so much I decided to attend Nashville Software School. I've always sought new experiences and challenges that keep my mind energized with unknown possibilities. It's been great and I'm very excited to see where it takes me!

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- · React, JavaScript
- · Python, Django
- · CSS, Bootstrap-react
- $\cdot$  HTML
- · Git, Github
- $\cdot \, \mathsf{Adobe} \, \mathsf{XD}$

# **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School

· Full Stack Developer Program, 2021

North Dakota State University

· BS in Construction Engineering, 2003

## **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

# Nashville Software School (2020 - 2021)

Intensive six month software development bootcamp with immersive, lab based learning and simulated work environment

- · Designed and built mobile first application in React
- · Worked with team members on multiple projects
- · Git and Github for version control
- · Dynamically rendered data with api's
- · Applied knowledge to interpret existing

#### **PORTFOLIO**

# Are you going?

https://github.com/leorondeau/are-you-going

"Are you going?" is an events app with a streamlined, simple scrolling experience that lists events and if people you know are going.

- · A minimalistic events only application built with React
- · Utilized ERDs for many to many user relationships
- Feature that notified users if their selected users were attending
- · CRUD for multiple users
- · Github project boards and issue tickets

# **Rare Publishing**

https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-44/rare-picnic-fish https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-44/rare-server-picnic-fish

NSS Group Project

- $\cdot$  Full stack application with React for client side and Python for server side
- $\cdot$  Wrote SQL statements to query and target resources in database
- · Worked in a SCRUM environment implementing agile estimation
- · Coordinated with team to distribute workload via issue tickets

## **Holiday Road**

https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-44/holiday-road-north-cascades

NSS Group Project

- · Worked with a team to develop a park tourism app
- $\cdot$  Used external weather API to pull data based on location
- · Components were managed with single responsibility principle
- · Site was designed to cater to a specific user
- · Git and Github workflow to reduce code conflicts

## **WORK HISTORY**

# Songwriter (2009 - Present)

Wrote songs and performed them throughout the United States, UK, Europe and Australia. I released multiple albums of my own material and had my songs recorded by other artists.

- · Booked domestic tours and coordinated with agents abroad
- · Managed band personnel merchandise designed and produced
- · Online sales and delivery
- · Coordinated video and recording projects

# **Beer Distributor (2012 - 2017)**

Kept track of hundreds of accounts in Austin TX for line maintenance and product delivery

- · Organized routes for maximum efficiency of time and resources
- · Serviced clients to insure great tasting beer
- · Coordinated with managers for responsive delivery
- · Acted as an ambassador for great German and Czech style beers

# **Production Scheduler (2005 - 2009)**

Master scheduler for all concrete produced and shipped. Ordered material and maximized bed space to follow just in time (JIT) principles and limit onsite storage.

- · Coordinated with project managers to ensure on time delivery
- · Insured that all products were ready to be shipped on time
- · Responded quickly to project schedule changes
- · Kept thorough records of all pieces in every project
- · Produced cost estimates for new projects